<SINT_Prompt_Task>
<Objective>
Generate a single, detailed, and technically complete Formal Definition (FD) to be used by the SINT Code Generator to create a SINT prompt that will in turn generate 4 different complex analytical tasks. Each of the 4 tasks must require a unique interdisciplinary approach with detailed expert analysis, numerical ratings (1-10), iterative convergence, and comprehensive synthesis.
</Objective>
<Context>
1. The 4 tasks must span fundamentally different domains to demonstrate the breadth of the SINT framework.
2. Each task must explicitly enforce numerical ratings (1-10), cross-evaluation between experts, and multi-round synthesis.
3. All outputs must be in English.
4. The methodology and agent configuration must reflect the nature of each task, ensuring either conflict (Step 3A) or consensus (Step 3B) paths when appropriate.
5. The Principle of Contextual Grounding (PCG) is mandatory: each thesis must reference Objective/Context.
</Context>
<Consultants>
<Agent id="A1" focus="Experiment Design and Reproducibility">Ensures the tasks elicit measurable, reproducible behaviors across models and runs.</Agent>
<Agent id="A2" focus="Multi-Agent Debate Dynamics">Optimizes the use of debates, criticism loops, and consensus formation rules.</Agent>
<Agent id="A3" focus="Evaluation & Metrics">Specifies rating schemes, cross-evaluation protocols, and verification checks.</Agent>
<Agent id="A4" focus="Domain Coverage Strategy">Ensures diversity of domains and suitability of expert roles per domain.</Agent>
</Consultants>
<Methodology>
Expert Debates (N=4) for the current System Designer step to achieve balanced synthesis across conflicting priorities. The resulting tasks must prescribe specific methodologies per case as follows:
- Case 2: Debates (N=3) with Conflict Scenario (Step 3A)
- Case 3: Debates (N=3) with Consensus Scenario (Step 3B)
- Case 4: Generator + External Critic (N=2)
- Case 5: Debates (N=4) with Conflict Scenario (Step 3A)
</Methodology>
<Finalization_Protocol>
1. The final FD must be self-contained and traceable to Context (PCG).
2. Include explicit instructions for ratings, cross-evaluation, and multi-round synthesis.
3. Require a Dual Output: Executive Summary (one-line + 3 bullets) and a Synthesized Conclusion (XML) plus a Verification Report.
4. Enforce strict XML-only outputs; no markdown wrappers, no leading spaces, no HTML tags/entities.
5. If any instruction conflicts or is impossible (MSV), the executor must stop and request clarification.
</Finalization_Protocol>
<Verification>
Include a Verification Report with checks for pcg_compliance, xml_validity, objective_match, and no_undeclared_assumptions; include meta: consensus_score (0-10), iterations_used (0-2), fallback_flag (boolean).
</Verification>
</SINT_Prompt_Task>
