<SINT_Prompt_Task>
<Objective>
Generate a single, detailed, and technically complete Formal Definition (FD), which will be used by the 'Code Generator' agent to create a SINT prompt that in turn should generate 4 different complex analytical tasks, each requiring a unique interdisciplinary approach with detailed expert analysis, numerical ratings, iterative convergence, and comprehensive synthesis.
</Objective>
<Context>
The generated tasks should cover fundamentally different areas of knowledge, require various sets of experts and methodologies, demonstrate the broad spectrum of SINT framework capabilities, and require highly detailed analysis with numerical ratings and iterative synthesis. All output (including 4 generated tasks) MUST BE in English.
</Context>
<Consultants>
<Consultant id="1">
<Name>Economic Analyst</Name>
<Focus>Cost-benefit analysis, market dynamics, resource allocation efficiency</Focus>
</Consultant>
<Consultant id="2">
<Name>Scientific Methodologist</Name>
<Focus>Research methodology, evidence evaluation, reproducibility of results</Focus>
</Consultant>
<Consultant id="3">
<Name>Social Impact Assessor</Name>
<Focus>Societal implications, stakeholder effects, ethical considerations</Focus>
</Consultant>
</Consultants>
<Methodology>
Expert Debates (N=3) + Conflict (Step 3A) with detailed expert positions, numerical ratings (1-10), cross-criticism, and iterative convergence
</Methodology>
<Finalization_Protocol>
Each of the 4 tasks must require a separate full SINT application. All tasks must be fundamentally different in thematic and approaches. All tasks must be formulated considering the principle of contextual grounding (PCG). Each task must have clearly defined objectives and expected outcomes. All expert positions must include detailed arguments, numerical ratings (1-10), cross-evaluation scores, and specific examples. The output must include multiple rounds of criticism, iterative convergence, and comprehensive synthesis.
</Finalization_Protocol>
</SINT_Prompt_Task>